<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<resources>

        <string-array name="titles">

            <item>Jumping Jacks</item>
            <item>Wall Sit</item>
            <item>Push Up</item>
            <item>Abdominal Crunch</item>
            <item>Step-Up onto Chair</item>
            <item>Squat</item>
            <item>Triceps dip on Chair</item>
            <item>Plank</item>
            <item>High Knees Running in place</item>
            <item >Lunge</item>
            <item>Push-up and Rotation</item>
            <item>Side Plank</item>
        </string-array>



 <string-array name="abd_exe">

    <item> 3\'4 Sit Ups Consists of The Following Steps : \n
         1. Lie down on the floor and secure your feet. Your legs should be bent at the knees.\n\n
         2. Place your hands behind or to the side of your head. You will begin with your back on the ground. This will be your starting position.\n\n
         3. Flex your hips and spine to raise your torso toward your knees.\n\n
         4. At the top of the contraction your torso should be perpendicular to the ground. Reverse the motion, going only 3 of 4 of the way down.\n\n
         5. Repeat for the recommended amount of repetitions.
    </item>

    <item> Cocoons Consists Of The Following Steps : \n
        1. Begin by lying on your back on the ground.Your legs should be straight and your arms extended behind your head. This will be your starting position.\n\n
        2. To perform the movement, tuck the knees toward your chest, rotating your pelvis to lift your glutes from the floor. As you do so, flex the spine, bringing your arms back over your head to perform a simultaneous crunch motion.\n\n
        3. After a brief pause, return to the starting position.
    </item>

    <item>Spider Crawl Consists Of The Following Steps : \n
        1. Begin in a prone position on the floor. Support your weight on your hands and toes, with your feet together and your body straight. Your arms should be bent to 90 degrees. This will be your starting position.\n\n
        2. Initiate the movement by raising one foot off of the ground. Externally rotate the leg and bring the knee toward your elbow, as far forward as possible.\n\n
        3. Return this leg to the starting position and repeat on the opposite side.
    </item>


    <item>Decline Crunch Consists Of Following Steps : \n
        1.Secure your legs at the end of the decline bench and lie down.\n\n
        2.Now place your hands lightly on either side of your head keeping your elbows in. Tip: Don\'t lock your fingers behind your head.\n\n
        3.While pushing the small of your back down in the bench to better isolate your abdominal muscles, begin to roll your shoulders off it.\n\n
        4.Continue to push down as hard as you can with your lower back as you contract your abdominals and exhale.Your shoulders should come up off the bench only about four inches,and your lower back should remain on the bench. At the top of the movement, contract your abdominals hard and keep the contraction for a second.\n Tip: Focus on slow, controlled movement - don\'t cheat yourself by using momentum.\n\n
        5.After the one second contraction, begin to come down slowly again to the starting position as you inhale.\n\n
        6.Repeat for the recommended amount of repetitions.

    </item>

    <item>Frog Situps Consists Of Following Steps : \n
        1. Lie with your back flat on the floor (or exercise mat) and your legs extended in front of you.\n\n
        2. Now bend at the knees and place your outer thighs by the floor (or mat) as you make the soles of your feet touch each other.\n\n
        3. Now try pushing both soles and bringing them up as near you as possible while you keep the outer thighs on the floor (or at least almost touching it). Tip: In this position your legs should create a diamond shape.\n\n
        4. Now, cross your arms in front of you by touching the opposite shoulders. This will be your starting position.\n\n
        5. As you exhale flatten your lower back to the floor while curling the torso upwards. Tip: This will be like performing the first 1/4 movement of a sit up. Hold at the top position for a second.\n\n
        6. As you inhale, slowly lower back to the starting position.\n\n
        7. Repeat for the recommended amount of repetitions.

    </item>

        <item>Russian Twist Consists Of Following Steps : \n

            1. Lie down on the floor placing your feet either under something that will not move or by having a partner hold them. Your legs should be bent at the knees.\n\n
            2. Elevate your upper body so that it creates an imaginary V-shape with your thighs. Your arms should be fully extended in front of you perpendicular to your torso and with the hands clasped. This is the starting position.\n\n
            3. Twist your torso to the right side until your arms are parallel with the floor while breathing out.\n\n
            4. Hold the contraction for a second and move back to the starting position while breathing out. Now move to the opposite side performing the same techniques you applied to the right side.\n\n
            5. Repeat for the recommended amount of repetitions.

        </item>

        <item>Hanging Leg Raise Consists Of Following Steps : \n
            1. Hang from a chin-up bar with both arms extended at arms length in top of you using either a wide grip or a medium grip. The legs should be straight down with the pelvis rolled slightly backwards. This will be your starting position.\n\n
            2. Raise your legs until the torso makes a 90-degree angle with the legs. Exhale as you perform this movement and hold the contraction for a second or so.\n\n
            3. Go back slowly to the starting position as you breathe in.\n\n
            4. Repeat for the recommended amount of repetitions.


        </item>

        <item>Hanging Pike Consists Of Following Steps : \n

            1. Hang from a chin-up bar with your legs and feet together using an overhand grip (palms facing away from you) that is slightly wider than shoulder width. Tip: You may use wrist wraps in order to facilitate holding on to the bar.\n\n
            2. Now bend your knees at a 90 degree angle and bring the upper legs forward so that the calves are perpendicular to the floor while the thighs remain parallel to it. This will be your starting position.\n\n
            3. Pull your legs up as you exhale until you almost touch your shins with the bar above you. Tip: Try to straighten your legs as much as possible while at the top.\n\n
            4. Lower your legs as slowly as possible until you reach the starting position.\n Tip: Avoid swinging and using momentum at all times.\n\n
            5. Repeat for the recommended amount of repetitions
        </item>
 </string-array>


 <string-array name="back_exe">

        <item>Bentover Barbell Row Consists Of Following Steps : \n

          1. Holding a barbell with a pronated grip (palms facing down), bend your knees slightly and bring your torso forward, by bending at the waist, while keeping the back straight until it is almost parallel to the floor. Tip: Make sure that you keep the head up. The barbell should hang directly in front of you as your arms hang perpendicular to the floor and your torso. This is your starting position.\n\n
          2. Now, while keeping the torso stationary, breathe out and lift the barbell to you. Keep the elbows close to the body and only use the forearms to hold the weight. At the top contracted position, squeeze the back muscles and hold for a brief pause.\n\n
          3. Then inhale and slowly lower the barbell back to the starting position.\n\n
          4. Repeat for the recommended amount of repetitions.

        </item>


        <item>Hyper Extensions Consists Of Following Steps :\n

        1. Lie face down on a hyperextension bench, tucking your ankles securely under the footpads.\n\n
        2. Adjust the upper pad if possible so your upper thighs lie flat across the wide pad, leaving enough room for you to bend at the waist without any restriction.\n\n
        3. With your body straight, cross your arms in front of you (my preference) or behind your head. This will be your starting position.\n Tip: You can also hold a weight plate for extra resistance in front of you under your crossed arms.\n\n
        4. Start bending forward slowly at the waist as far as you can while keeping your back flat. Inhale as you perform this movement. Keep moving forward until you feel a nice stretch on the hamstrings and you can no longer keep going without a rounding of the back.Tip: Never round the back as you perform this exercise. Also, some people can go farther than others. The key thing is that you go as far as your body allows you to without rounding the back.\n\n
        5. Slowly raise your torso back to the initial position as you inhale. Tip: Avoid the temptation to arch your back past a straight line. Also, do not swing the torso at any time in order to protect the back from injury.\n\n
        6. Repeat for the recommended amount of repetitions.
        </item>

        <item>Pull-up\'s Consists Of Following Steps :\n

1. Grab the pull-up bar with the palms facing forward using the prescribed grip. Note on grips: For a wide grip, your hands need to be spaced out at a distance wider than your shoulder width. For a medium grip, your hands need to be spaced out at a distance equal to your shoulder width and for a close grip at a distance smaller than your shoulder width.\n\n
2. As you have both arms extended in front of you holding the bar at the chosen grip width, bring your torso back around 30 degrees or so while creating a curvature on your lower back and sticking your chest out. This is your starting position.\n\n
3. Pull your torso up until the bar touches your upper chest by drawing the shoulders and the upper arms down and back. Exhale as you perform this portion of the movement. Tip: Concentrate on squeezing the back muscles once you reach the full contracted position. The upper torso should remain stationary as it moves through space and only the arms should move. The forearms should do no other work other than hold the bar.\n\n
4. After a second on the contracted position, start to inhale and slowly lower your torso back to the starting position when your arms are fully extended and the lats are fully stretched.\n\n
5. Repeat this motion for the prescribed amount of repetitions.

        </item>

        <item>Barbell Dead Lift Consists Of Following Steps : \n
1. Stand in front of a loaded barbell.\n
2. While keeping the back as straight as possible, bend your knees, bend forward and grasp the bar using a medium (shoulder width) overhand grip. This will be the starting position of the exercise. Tip: If it is difficult to hold on to the bar with this grip, alternate your grip or use wrist straps.\n\n
3. While holding the bar, start the lift by pushing with your legs while simultaneously getting your torso to the upright position as you breathe out. In the upright position, stick your chest out and contract the back by bringing the shoulder blades back. Think of how the soldiers in the military look when they are in standing in attention.\n\n
4. Go back to the starting position by bending at the knees while simultaneously leaning the torso forward at the waist while keeping the back straight. When the weights on the bar touch the floor you are back at the starting position and ready to perform another repetition.\n\n
5. Perform the amount of repetitions prescribed in the program.\n\n
        </item>

        <item>One Arm Kettlebell Row Consists Of Following Steps :\n

            1.Place a kettlebell in front of your feet.\n\n
            2.Bend your knees slightly and then push your butt out as much as possible as you bend over to get in the starting position. Grab the kettlebell and pull it to your stomach, retracting your shoulder blade and flexing the elbow.\n\n
            3.Keep your back straight Lower and repeat.

        </item>


        <item>Weighted Pull-up\'s Consists Of Following Steps : \n

1. Attach a weight to a dip belt and secure it around your waist. Grab the pull-up bar with the palms of your hands facing forward. For a medium grip, your hands should be spaced at shoulder width. Both arms should be extended in front of you holding the bar at the chosen grip.\n\n
2. You want to bring your torso back about 30 degrees while creating a curvature in your lower back and sticking your chest out. This will be your starting position.\n\n
3. Now, exhale and pull your torso up until your head is above your hands. Concentrate on squeezing yourshoulder blades back and down as you reach the top contracted position.\n\n
4. After a brief moment at the top contracted position, inhale and slowly lower your torso back to the starting position with your arms extended and your lats fully stretched.

        </item>


        <item>Atlast Stone Consists Of Following Steps : \n

1. Begin with the atlas stone between your feet. Bend at the hips to wrap your arms vertically around the Atlas Stone, attempting to get your fingers underneath the stone. Many stones will have a small flat portion on the bottom, which will make the stone easier to hold.\n\n
2. Pulling the stone into your torso, drive through the back half of your feet to pull the stone from the ground.\n\n
3. As the stone passes the knees, lap it by sitting backward, pulling the stone on top of your thighs.\n\n
4. Sit low, getting the stone high onto your chest as you change your grip to reach over the stone. Stand, driving through with your hips. Close distance to the loading platform, and lean back, extending the hips to get the stone as high as possible.

        </item>


        <item>Mixed Grip Chin Consists Of Following Steps : \n

1. Using a spacing that is just about 1 inch wider than shoulder width, grab a pull-up bar with the palms of one hand facing forward and the palms of the other hand facing towards you. This will be your starting position.\n\n
2. Now start to pull yourself up as you exhale. Tip: With the arm that has the palms facing up concentrate on using the back muscles in order to perform the movement. The elbow of that arm should remain close to the torso. With the other arm that has the palms facing forward, the elbows will be away but in line with the torso. You will concentrate on using the lats to pull your body up.\n\n
3. After a second contraction at the top, start to slowly come down as you inhale.\n\n
4. Repeat for the recommended amount of repetitions.\n\n
5. On the following set, switch grips; so if you had the right hand with the palms facing you and the left one with the palms facing forward, on the next set you will have the palms facing forward for the right hand and facing you for the left.
        </item>
 </string-array>


 <string-array name="biceps_exe">



    <item>Barbell Curl Consists Of Following Steps : \n

1. Stand up with your torso upright while holding a barbell at a shoulder-width grip. The palm of your hands should be facing forward and the elbows should be close to the torso. This will be your starting position.\n\n
2. While holding the upper arms stationary, curl the weights forward while contracting the biceps as you breathe out. Tip: Only the forearms should move.\n\n
3. Continue the movement until your biceps are fully contracted and the bar is at shoulder level. Hold the contracted position for a second and squeeze the biceps hard.\n\n
4. Slowly begin to bring the bar back to starting position as your breathe in.\n\n
5. Repeat for the recommended amount of repetitions.
    </item>

    <item> Incline Inner Biceps Curl Consists Of Following Steps : \n

1. Hold a dumbbell in each hand and lie back on an incline bench.\n\n
2. The dumbbells should be at arm\'s length hanging at your sides and your palms should be facing out. This will be your starting position.\n
3. Now as you exhale curl the weight outward and up while keeping your forearms in line with your side deltoids. Continue the curl until the dumbbells are at shoulder height and to the sides of your deltoids.\n Tip: The end of the movement should look similar to a double biceps pose.\n\n
4. After a second contraction at the top of the movement, start to inhale and slowly lower the weights back to the starting position using the same path used to bring them up.\n\n
5. Repeat for the recommended amount of repetitions.
    </item>

    <item>Standing Concentration Curl Consists Of Following Steps : \n

1. Taking a dumbbell in your working hand, lean forward. Allow your working arm to hang perpendicular to the ground with the elbow pointing out. This will be your starting position.\n\n
2. Flex the elbow to curl the weight, keeping the upper arm stationary. At the top of the repetition, flex the biceps and pause.\n\n
3. Lower the dumbbell back to the starting position.\n\n
4. Repeat the movement for the prescribed amount of repetitions.
    </item>

    <item>Grip Concentration Curl Consists Of Following Steps : \n
1. Sit down on a flat bench with a barbell or E-Z Bar in front of you in between your legs. Your legs should be spread with the knees bent and the feet on the floor.\n\n
2. Use your arms to pick the barbell up and place the back of your upper arms on top of your inner thighs (around three and a half inches away from the front of the knee). A supinated grip closer than shoulder width is needed to perform this exercise.\n Tip: Your arm should be extended at arms length and the barbell should be above the floor. This will be your starting position.\n\n
3. While holding the upper arms stationary, curl the weights forward while contracting the biceps as you breathe out. Only the forearms should move. Continue the movement until your biceps are fully contracted and the dumbbells are at shoulder level. Hold the contracted position for a second as you squeeze the biceps.\n\n
4. Slowly begin to bring the barbell back to starting position as your breathe in. Tip: Avoid swinging motions at any time.\n\n
5. Repeat for the recommended amount of repetitions.

    </item>

    <item>OverHead Cable Curl Consists Of Following Steps : \n

1. To begin, set a weight that is comfortable on each side of the pulley machine. Note: Make sure that the amount of weight selected is the same on each side.\n\n
2. Now adjust the height of the pulleys on each side and make sure that they are positioned at a height higher than that of your shoulders.\n\n
3. Stand in the middle of both sides and use an underhand grip (palms facing towards the ceiling) to grab each handle. Your arms should be fully extended and parallel to the floor with your feet positioned shoulder width apart from each other. Your body should be evenly aligned the handles. This is the starting position.\n\n
4. While exhaling, slowly squeeze the biceps on each side until your forearms and biceps touch.\n\n
5. While inhaling, move your forearms back to the starting position. Note: Your entire body is stationary during this exercise except for the forearms.\n\n
6. Repeat for the recommended amount of repetitions prescribed in your program.

    </item>

    <item>Standing One-Arm Cable Curl Consists Of Following Steps : \n

1. Start out by grabbing single handle next to the low pulley machine. Make sure you are far enough from the machine so that your arm is supporting the weight.\n\n
2. Make sure that your upper arm is stationary, perpendicular to the floor with elbows in and palms facing forward. Your non lifting arm should be grabbing your waist.This will allow you to keep your balance.\n\n
3. Slowly begin to curl the single handle upwards while keeping the upper arm stationary until your forearm touches your bicep while exhaling. Tip: Only the forearm should move.\n\n
4. Hold the contraction position as you squeeze the bicep and then lower the single handle back down to the starting position as you inhale.\n\n
5. Repeat for the recommended amount of repetitions.\n\n
6. Switch arms while performing this exercise.

    </item>



 </string-array>


 <string-array name="calves_exe">

    <item>Calf Press Consists Of Following Steps : \n

1. Adjust the seat so that your legs are only slightly bent in the start position. The balls of your feet should be firmly on the platform.\n\n
2. Select an appropriate weight, and grasp the handles. This will be your starting position.\n\n
3. Straighten the legs by extending the knees, just barely lifting the weight from the stack. Your ankle should be fully flexed, toes pointing up. Execute the movement by pressing downward through the balls of your feet as far as possible.\n\n
4. After a brief pause, reverse the motion and repeat.
    </item>

    <item>Smith Machine Calf Raises Consists Of Following Steps : \n

1. Place a block or weight plate below the bar on the Smith machine. Set the bar to a position that best matches your height. Once the correct height is chosen and the bar is loaded, step onto the plates with the balls of your feet and place the bar on the back of your shoulders.\n\n
2. Take the bar with both hands facing forward. Rotate the bar to unrack it. This will be your starting position.\n\n
3. Raise your heels as high as possible by pushing off of the balls of your feet, flexing your calf at the top of the contraction. Your knees should remain extended. Hold the contracted position for a second before you start to go back down.\n\n
4. Return slowly to the starting position as you breathe in while lowering your heels.\n\n
5. Repeat for the recommended amount of repetitions.

    </item>

    <item>Standing Calf Raises Consists Of Following Steps : \n

1. Adjust the padded lever of the calf raise machine to fit your height.\n\n
2. Place your shoulders under the pads provided and position your toes facing forward (or using any of the two other positions described at the beginning of the chapter). The balls of your feet should be secured on top of the calf block with the heels extending off it. Push the lever up by extending your hips and knees until your torso is standing erect. The knees should be kept with a slight bend; never locked. Toes should be facing forward, outwards or inwards as described at the beginning of the chapter. This will be your starting position.\n\n
3. Raise your heels as you breathe out by extending your ankles as high as possible and flexing your calf. Ensure that the knee is kept stationary at all times. There should be no bending at any time. Hold the contracted position by a second before you start to go back down.\n\n
4. Go back slowly to the starting position as you breathe in by lowering your heels as you bend the ankles until calves are stretched.\n\n
5. Repeat for the recommended amount of repetitions.

    </item>

    <item>Donkey Calf Raises Consists Of Following Steps : \n

1. For this exercise you will need access to a donkey calf raise machine. Start by positioning your lower back and hips under the padded lever provided. The tailbone area should be the one making contact with the pad.\n\n
2. Place both of your arms on the side handles and place the balls of your feet on the calf block with the heels extending off. Align the toes forward, inward or outward, depending on the area you wish to target, and straighten the knees without locking them. This will be your starting position.\n\n
3. Raise your heels as you breathe out by extending your ankles as high as possible and flexing your calf. Ensure that the knee is kept stationary at all times. There should be no bending at any time. Hold the contracted position by a second before you start to go back down.\n\n
4. Go back slowly to the starting position as you breathe in by lowering your heels as you bend the ankles until calves are stretched.\n\n
5. Repeat for the recommended amount of repetitions.

    </item>


    <item>Standing Dumbell Calf Raise Consists Of Following Steps : \n

1. Stand with your torso upright holding two dumbbells in your hands by your sides. Place the ball of the foot on a sturdy and stable wooden board (that is around 2-3 inches tall) while your heels extend off and touch the floor. This will be your starting position.\n\n
2. With the toes pointing either straight (to hit all parts equally), inwards (for emphasis on the outer head) or outwards (for emphasis on the inner head), raise the heels off the floor as you exhale by contracting the calves. Hold the top contraction for a second.\n\n
3. As you inhale, go back to the starting position by slowly lowering the heels.\n\n
4. Repeat for the recommended amount of times.

    </item>
 </string-array>



 <string-array name="chest_exe">

    <item>Decline Dumbell Flyes Consists Of Following Steps : \n

1. Secure your legs at the end of the decline bench and lie down with a dumbbell on each hand on top of your thighs. The palms of your hand will be facing each other.\n\n
2. Once you are laying down, move the dumbbells in front of you at shoulder width. The palms of the hands should be facing each other and the arms should be perpendicular to the floor and fully extended. This will be your starting position.\n\n
3. With a slight bend on your elbows in order to prevent stress at the biceps tendon, lower your arms out at both sides in a wide arc until you feel a stretch on your chest. Breathe in as you perform this portion of the movement.\n Tip: Keep in mind that throughout the movement, the arms should remain stationary; the movement should only occur at the shoulder joint.\n\n
4. Return your arms back to the starting position as you squeeze your chest muscles and breathe out. Tip: Make sure to use the same arc of motion used to lower the weights.\n\n
5. Hold for a second at the contracted position and repeat the movement for the prescribed amount of repetitions.
    </item>

    <item>Dumbell Bench Press Consists Of Following Steps : \n

1. Lie down on a flat bench with a dumbbell in each hand resting on top of your thighs. The palms of your hands will be facing each other.\n\n
2. Then, using your thighs to help raise the dumbbells up, lift the dumbbells one at a time so that you can hold them in front of you at shoulder width.\n\n
3. Once at shoulder width, rotate your wrists forward so that the palms of your hands are facing away from you. The dumbbells should be just to the sides of your chest, with your upper arm and forearm creating a 90 degree angle. Be sure to maintain full control of the dumbbells at all times. This will be your starting position.\n
4. Then, as you breathe out, use your chest to push the dumbbells up. Lock your arms at the top of the lift and squeeze your chest, hold for a second and then begin coming down slowly.\n Tip: Ideally, lowering the weight should take about twice as long as raising it.\n\n
5. Repeat the movement for the prescribed amount of repetitions of your training program.

    </item>


    <item>Low Cable Crossover Consists Of Following Steps : \n

1. To move into the starting position, place the pulleys at the low position, select the resistance to be used and grasp a handle in each hand.\n\n
2. Step forward, gaining tension in the pulleys. Your palms should be facing forward, hands below the waist, and your arms straight. This will be your starting position.\n\n
3. With a slight bend in your arms, draw your hands upward and toward the midline of your body. Your hands should come together in front of your chest, palms facing up.\n\n
4. Return your arms back to the starting position after a brief pause.

    </item>


    <item>Push-Up\'s Consists Of Following Steps : \n

1. Lie on the floor face down and place your hands about 36 inches apart while holding your torso up at arms length.\n\n
2. Next, lower yourself downward until your chest almost touches the floor as you inhale.\n\n
3. Now breathe out and press your upper body back up to the starting position while squeezing your chest.\n\n
4. After a brief pause at the top contracted position, you can begin to lower yourself downward again for as many repetitions as needed.

    </item>

    <item>Bodyweight Flyes Consists Of Following Steps : \n
1. Position two equally loaded EZ bars on the ground next to each other. Ensure they are able to roll.\n\n
2. Assume a push-up position over the bars, supporting your weight on your toes and hands with your arms extended and body straight.\n\n
3. Place your hands on the bars. This will be your starting position.\n\n
4. Using a slow and controlled motion, move your hands away from the midline of your body, rolling the bars apart. Inhale during this portion of the motion.\n\n
5. After moving the bars as far apart as you can, return to the starting position by pulling them back together. Exhale as you perform this movement.
    </item>

    <item>Dips-Chest Version Consists Of Following Steps : \n

1. For this exercise you will need access to parallel bars. To get yourself into the starting position, hold your body at arms length (arms locked) above the bars.\n\n
2. While breathing in, lower yourself slowly with your torso leaning forward around 30 degrees or so and your elbows flared out slightly until you feel a slight stretch in the chest.\n\n
3. Once you feel the stretch, use your chest to bring your body back to the starting position as you breathe out. Tip: Remember to squeeze the chest at the top of the movement for a second.\n\n
4. Repeat the movement for the prescribed amount of repetitions.

    </item>

    <item>Neck Press Consists Of Following Steps : \n
1. Lie back on a flat bench. Using a medium-width grip (a grip that creates a 90-degree angle in the middle of the movement between the forearms and the upper arms), lift the bar from the rack and hold it straight over your neck with your arms locked. This will be your starting position.\n\n
2. As you breathe in, come down slowly until you feel the bar on your neck.\n\n
3. After a second pause, bring the bar back to the starting position as you breathe out and push the bar using your chest muscles. Lock your arms and squeeze your chest in the contracted position, hold for a second and then start coming down slowly again.\n Tip: It should take at least twice as long to go down than to come up).\n\n
4. Repeat the movement for the prescribed amount of repetitions.\n\n
5. When you are done, place the bar back in the rack.



    </item>

    <item>Plyo Kettle BellPush-up\'s Consists Of Following Steps : \n
1. Place a kettlebell on the floor. Place yourself in a pushup position, on your toes with one hand on the ground and one hand holding the kettlebell, with your elbows extended. This will be your starting position.\n\n
2. Begin by lowering yourself as low as you can, keeping your back straight.\n\n
3. Quickly and forcefully reverse direction, pushing yourself up to the other side of the kettlebell, switching hands as you do so. Continue the movement by descending and repeating the movement back and fort

    </item>
 </string-array>

 <string-array name="quads_exe">

    <item>Barbell Squats Consists Of Following Steps : \n

1. This exercise is best performed inside a squat rack for safety purposes. To begin, first set the bar on a rack to just below shoulder level. Once the correct height is chosen and the bar is loaded, step under the bar and place the back of your shoulders (slightly below the neck) across it.\n\n
2. Hold on to the bar using both arms at each side and lift it off the rack by first pushing with your legs and at the same time straightening your torso.\n\n
3. Step away from the rack and position your legs using a shoulder width medium stance with the toes slightly pointed out. Keep your head up at all times and also maintain a straight back. This will be your starting position.\n (Note: For the purposes of this discussion we will use the medium stance described above which targets overall development; however you can choose any of the three stances discussed in the foot stances section).\n\n
4. egin to slowly lower the bar by bending the knees and hips as you maintain a straight posture with the head up. Continue down until the angle between the upper leg and the calves becomes slightly less than 90-degrees. Inhale as you perform this portion of the movement. Tip: If you performed the exercise correctly, the front of the knees should make an imaginary straight line with the toes that is perpendicular to the front. If your knees are past that imaginary line (if they are past your toes) then you are placing undue stress on the knee and the exercise has been performed incorrectly.\n\n
5. Begin to raise the bar as you exhale by pushing the floor with the heel of your foot as you straighten the legs again and go back to the starting position.\n\n
6. Repeat for the recommended amount of repetitions

    </item>


    <item>Barbell Walking Lunge Consists Of Following Steps : \n

1. Begin standing with your feet shoulder width apart and a barbell across your upper back.\n\n
2. Step forward with one leg, flexing the knees to drop your hips. Descend until your rear knee nearly touches the ground. Your posture should remain upright, and your front knee should stay above the front foot.\n\n
3. Drive through the heel of your lead foot and extend both knees to raise yourself back up.\n\n
4. Step forward with your rear foot, repeating the lunge on the opposite leg.

    </item>

    <item>Goblet Squat Consists Of Following Steps : \n
1. Stand holding a light kettlebell by the horns close to your chest. This will be your starting position.\n\n
2. Squat down between your legs until your hamstrings are on your calves. Keep your chest and head up and your back straight.\n\n
3. At the bottom position, pause and use your elbows to push your knees out. Return to the starting position, and repeat for 10-20 repetitions.
    </item>

    <item>Trap Bar Deadlift Consists Of Following Steps : \n
1. For this exercise load a trap bar, also known as a hex bar, to an appropriate weight resting on the ground. Stand in the center of the apparatus and grasp both handles.\n\n
2. Lower your hips, look forward with your head and keep your chest up.\n\n
3. Begin the movement by driving through the heels and extend your hips and knees. Avoid rounding your back at all times.\n\n
4 .At the completion of the movement, lower the weight back to the ground under control.
    </item>

    <item>Hang Clean Consists Of Following Steps : \n
1. Begin with a shoulder width, double overhand or hook grip, with the bar hanging at the mid thigh position. Your back should be straight and inclined slightly forward.\n\n
2. Begin by aggressively extending through the hips, knees and ankles, driving the weight upward. As you do so, shrug your shoulders towards your ears.\n\n
3. As full extension is achieved, transition into the final pull by aggressively shrugging and flexing the arms with the elbows up and out. At peak extension, aggressively pull yourself down, rotating your elbows under the bar as you do so. Receive the bar in a front squat position, the depth of which is dependent upon the height of the bar at the end of the third pull. The bar should be racked onto the protracted shoulders, lightly touching the throat with the hands relaxed. Continue to descend to the bottom squat position, which will help in the recovery.\n\n
4. Immediately recover by driving through the heels, keeping the torso upright and elbows up. Continue until you have risen to a standing position.
    </item>

    <item>Narrow Stance Squats Consists Of Following Steps : \n
1. This exercise is best performed inside a squat rack for safety purposes. To begin, first set the bar on a rack that best matches your height. Once the correct height is chosen and the bar is loaded, step under the bar and place the back of your shoulders (slightly below the neck) across it.\n\n
2. Hold on to the bar using both arms at each side and lift it off the rack by first pushing with your legs and at the same time straightening your torso.\n\n
3. Step away from the rack and position your legs using a less-than-shoulder-width narrow stance with the toes slightly pointed out. Feet should be around 3-6 inches apart. Keep your head up at all times (looking down will get you off balance) and maintain a straight back. This will be your starting position.\n (Note: For the purposes of this discussion we will use the medium stance described above which targets overall development; however you can choose any of the three stances discussed in the foot stances section).\n\n
4. Begin to slowly lower the bar by bending the knees as you maintain a straight posture with the head up. Continue down until the angle between the upper leg and the calves becomes slightly less than 90-degrees (which is the point in which the upper legs are below parallel to the floor). Inhale as you perform this portion of the movement. Tip: If you performed the exercise correctly, the front of the knees should make an imaginary straight line with the toes that is perpendicular to the front. If your knees are past that imaginary line (if they are past your toes) then you are placing undue stress on the knee and the exercise has been performed incorrectly.\n\n
5. Begin to raise the bar as you exhale by pushing the floor with the heel of your foot mainly as you straighten the legs again and go back to the starting position.\n\n
6. Repeat for the recommended amount of repetitions.
    </item>

    <item>Rope Jumping Consists Of Following Steps : \n
1. Hold an end of the rope in each hand. Position the rope behind you on the ground. Raise your arms up and turn the rope over your head bringing it down in front of you. When it reaches the ground, jump over it. Find a good turning pace that can be maintained. Different speeds and techniques can be used to introduce variation.\n\n
2. Rope jumping is exciting, challenges your coordination, and requires a lot of energy. A 150 lb person will burn about 350 calories jumping rope for 30 minutes, compared to over 450 calories running.
    </item>

    <item>Box Squats With Bands Consists Of Following Steps : \n
1. Begin in a power rack with a box at the appropriate height behind you. Set up the bands on the sleeves, secured to either band pegs, the rack, or dumbbells so that there is appropriate tension. If dumbbells are used, secure them so that they don\'t move. Also, ensure that the dumbbells you are using are heavy enough for the bands that you are using. Additional plates can be used to hold the dumbbells down. If more tension is needed, you can either widen the base on the floor or choke the bands. Typically, you would aim for a box height that brings you to a parallel squat, but you can train higher or lower if desired.\n\n
2. Begin by stepping under the bar and placing it across the back of the shoulders. Squeeze your shoulder blades together and rotate your elbows forward, attempting to bend the bar across your shoulders. Remove the bar from the rack, creating a tight arch in your lower back, and step back into position. Place your feet wider for more emphasis on the back, glutes, adductors, and hamstrings, or closer together for more quad development. Keep your head facing forward.\n\n
3. With your back, shoulders, and core tight, push your knees and butt out and you begin your descent. Sit back with your hips until you are seated on the box. Ideally, your shins should be perpendicular to the ground. Pause when you reach the box, and relax the hip flexors. Never bounce off of a box.\n\n
4. Keeping the weight on your heels and pushing your feet and knees out, drive upward off of the box as you lead the movement with your head. Continue upward, maintaining tightness head to toe. Use care to return the barbell to the rack.
    </item>

    <item>Kettlebell Pistol Squat Consists Of Following Steps : \n
1. Pick up a kettlebell with two hands and hold it by the horns. Hold one leg off of the floor and squat down on the other.\n\n
2. Squat down by flexing the knee and sitting back with the hips, holding the kettlebell up in front of you.\n\n
3. Hold the bottom position for a second and then reverse the motion, driving through the heel and keeping your head and chest up.\n\n
4. Lower yourself again and repeat.\n\n
    </item>

    <item>One Leg Barbell Squat Consists Of Following Steps : \n
1. Start by standing about 2 to 3 feet in front of a flat bench with your back facing the bench. Have a barbell in front of you on the floor.\n Tip: Your feet should be shoulder width apart from each other.\n\n
2. Bend the knees and use a pronated grip with your hands being wider than shoulder width apart from each other to lift the barbell up until you can rest it on your chest.\n\n
3. Then lift the barbell over your head and rest it on the base of your neck. Move one foot back so that your toe is resting on the flat bench. Your other foot should be stationary in front of you. Keep your head up at all times as looking down will get you off balance and also maintain a straight back.\n Tip: Make sure your back is straight and chest is out while performing this exercise.\n\n
4. As you inhale, slowly lower your leg until your thigh is parallel to the floor. At this point, your knee should be over your toes. Your chest should be directly above the middle of your thigh.\n\n
5. Leading with the chest and hips and contracting the quadriceps, elevate your leg back to the starting position as you exhale.\n\n
6. Repeat for the recommended amount of repetitions.\n
7. Switch legs and repeat the movement
    </item>
 </string-array>


 <string-array name="shoulders_exe">

    <item>Car Drivers Consists Of Following Steps : \n
1. While standing upright, hold a barbell plate in both hands at the 3 and 9 o\'clock positions. Your palms should be facing each other and your arms should be extended straight out in front of you. This will be your starting position.\n\n
2. Initiate the movement by rotating the plate as far to one side as possible. Use the same type of movement you would use to turn a steering wheel to one side.\n\n
3. Reverse the motion, turning it all the way to the opposite side.\n\n
4. Repeat for the recommended amount of repetitions.
    </item>

    <item>Front Two-Dumbbell Raise Consists Of Following Steps : \n
1. Pick a couple of dumbbells and stand with a straight torso and the dumbbells on front of your thighs at arms length with the palms of the hand facing your thighs. This will be your starting position.\n\n
2. While maintaining the torso stationary (no swinging), lift the dumbbells to the front with a slight bend on the elbow and the palms of the hands always facing down. Continue to go up until you arms are slightly above parallel to the floor. Exhale as you execute this portion of the movement and pause for a second at the top.\n\n
3. As you inhale, lower the dumbbells back down slowly to the starting position.\n\n
4. Repeat for the recommended amount of repetitions.
    </item>

    <item>OneArm-Dumbbell Press Consists Of Following Steps : \n
1. Start by having a dumbbell in one hand with your arm fully extended to the side using a neutral grip. Use your other arm to hold on to an incline bench to keep your balance.\n\n
2. Your feet should be shoulder width apart from each other. Now slowly lift the dumbbell up until you create a 90 degree angle with your arm. Note: Your forearm should be perpendicular to the floor. Continue to maintain a neutral grip throughout the entire exercise.\n\n
3. Slowly lift the dumbbell up until your arm is fully extended. This the starting position.\n\n
4. While inhaling lower the weight down until your arm is at a 90 degree angle again.\n\n
5. Feel the contraction for a second and then lift the weight back up towards the starting position while exhaling. Remember to hold on to the incline bench and keep your feet positioned to keep balance during the exercise.\n\n
6. Repeat for the recommended amount of repetitions.\n\n
7. Switch arms and repeat the exercise.
    </item>

    <item>Power Partials Consists Of Following Steps : \n
1. Stand up with your torso upright and a dumbbell on each hand being held at arms length. The elbows should be close to the torso.\n\n
2. The palms of the hands should be facing your torso. Your feet should be about shoulder width apart. This will be your starting position.\n\n
3. Keeping your arms straight and the torso stationary, lift the weights out to your sides until they are about shoulder level height while exhaling.\n\n
4. Feel the contraction for a second and begin to lower the weights back down to the starting position while inhaling. Tip: Keep the palms facing down with the little finger slightly higher while lifting and lowering the weights as it will concentrate the stress on your shoulders mainly.\n\n
5. Repeat for the recommended amount of repetitions.
    </item>

    <item>Kettlebell Thruster Consists Of Following Steps : \n
1. Clean two kettlebells to your shoulders. Clean the kettlebells to your shoulders by extending through the legs and hips as you pull the kettlebells towards your shoulders. Rotate your wrists as you do so. This will be your starting position.\n\n
2. Begin to squat by flexing your hips and knees, lowering your hips between your legs. Maintain an upright, straight back as you descend as low as you can.\n\n
3. At the bottom, reverse direction and squat by extending your knees and hips, driving through your heels. As you do so, press both kettlebells overhead by extending your arms straight up, using the momentum from the squat to help drive the weights upward.\n\n
4. As you begin the next repetition, return the weights to the shoulders
    </item>

    <item>Lying Rear Delt Raise Consists Of Following Steps : \n
1. While holding a dumbbell in each hand, lay with your chest down on a flat bench.\n\n
2. Position the palms of the hands in a neutral manner (palms facing your torso) as you keep the arms extended with the elbows slightly bent. This will be your starting position.\n\n
3. Now raise the arms to the side until your elbows are at shoulder height and your arms are roughly parallel to the floor as you exhale.\n Tip: Maintain your arms perpendicular to the torso while keeping them extended throughout the movement. Also, keep the contraction at the top for a second.\n\n
4. Slowly lower the dumbbells to the starting position as you inhale.\n\n
5. Repeat for the recommended amount of repetitions and then switch to the other arm.
    </item>

    <item>Seated Barbell Military Press Consists Of Following Steps : \n
1. Sit on a Military Press Bench with a bar behind your head and either have a spotter give you the bar (better on the rotator cuff this way) or pick it up yourself carefully with a pronated grip (palms facing forward).\n Tip: Your grip should be wider than shoulder width and it should create a 90-degree angle between the forearm and the upper arm as the barbell goes down.\n\n
2. Once you pick up the barbell with the correct grip length, lift the bar up over your head by locking your arms. Hold at about shoulder level and slightly in front of your head. This is your starting position.\n\n
3. Lower the bar down to the collarbone slowly as you inhale.\n\n
4. Lift the bar back up to the starting position as you exhale.\n\n
5. Repeat for the recommended amount of repetitions.
    </item>

    <item>HandStand Push-up\'s Consists Of Following Steps : \n
1. With your back to the wall bend at the waist and place both hands on the floor at shoulder width.\n\n
2. Kick yourself up against the wall with your arms straight. Your body should be upside down with the arms and legs fully extended. Keep your whole body as straight as possible.\n Tip: If doing this for the first time, have a spotter help you. Also, make sure that you keep facing the wall with your head, rather than looking down.\n\n
3. Slowly lower yourself to the ground as you inhale until your head almost touches the floor. Tip: It is of utmost importance that you come down slow in order to avoid head injury.\n\n
4. Push yourself back up slowly as you exhale until your elbows are nearly locked.\n\n
5. Repeat for the recommended amount of repetitions.
    </item>

 </string-array>


 <string-array name="triceps_exe">

        <item>Decline EZ Bar Triceps Extension Consists Of Following Steps : \n
        1. Secure your legs at the end of the decline bench and slowly lay down on the bench.\n\n
2. Using a close grip (a grip that is slightly less than shoulder width), lift the EZ bar from the rack and hold it straight over you with your arms locked and elbows in. The arms should be perpendicular to the floor. This will be your starting position.\n Tip: In order to protect your rotator cuff, it is best if you have a spotter help you lift the barbell off the rack.\n\n
3. As you breathe in and you keep the upper arms stationary, bring the bar down slowly by moving your forearms in a semicircular motion towards you until you feel the bar slightly touch your forehead. Breathe in as you perform this portion of the movement.\n\n
4. Lift the bar back to the starting position by contracting the triceps and exhaling.\n\n
5. Repeat until the recommended amount of repetitions is performed.
        </item>

        <item>Dips-Triceps Version Consists Of Following Steps : \n
1. To get into the starting position, hold your body at arm\'s length with your arms nearly locked above the bars.\n\n
2. Now, inhale and slowly lower yourself downward. Your torso should remain upright and your elbows should stay close to your body. This helps to better focus on tricep involvement. Lower yourself until there is a 90 degree angle formed between the upper arm and forearm.\n\n
3. Then, exhale and push your torso back up using your triceps to bring your body back to the starting position.\n\n
4. Repeat the movement for the prescribed amount of repetitions.
        </item>

        <item>Triceps Overhead With Extension Rope Consists Of Following Steps : \n
1. Attach a rope to a low pulley. After selecting an appropriate weight, grasp the rope with both hands and face away from the cable.\n\n
2. Position your hands behind your head with your elbows point straight up. Your elbows should start out flexed, and you can stagger your stance and lean gently away from the machine to create greater stability. This will be your starting position.\n\n
3. To perform the movement, extend through the elbow while keeping the upper arm in position, raising your hands above your head.\n\n
4. Squeeze your triceps at the top of the movement, and slowly lower the weight back to the start position.
        </item>

        <item>Body Up Consists Of Following Steps : \n
1. Assume a plank position on the ground. You should be supporting your bodyweight on your toes and forearms, keeping your torso straight. Your forearms should be shoulder-width apart. This will be your starting position.\n\n
2. Pressing your palms firmly into the ground, extend through the elbows to raise your body from the ground. Keep your torso rigid as you perform the movement.\n\n
3. Slowly lower your forearms back to the ground by allowing the elbows to flex.\n\n
4. Repeat
        </item>

        <item>Incline Barbell Triceps Extension Consists Of Following Steps : \n
1. Hold a barbell with an overhand grip (palms down) that is a little closer together than shoulder width.\n\n
2. Lie back on an incline bench set at any angle between 45-75-degrees.\n\n
3. Bring the bar overhead with your arms extended and elbows in. The arms should be in line with the torso above the head. This will be your starting position.\n\n
4. Now lower the bar in a semicircular motion behind your head until your forearms touch your biceps. Inhale as you perform this movement. Tip: Keep your upper arms stationary and close to your head at all times. Only the forearms should move.\n\n
5. Return to the starting position as you breathe out and you contract the triceps. Hold the contraction for a second.\n\n
6. Repeat for the recommended amount of repetitions.
        </item>

        <item>Weighted Bench Dip Consists Of Following Steps : \n
1. For this exercise you will need to place a bench behind your back and another one in front of you. With the benches perpendicular to your body, hold on to one bench on its edge with the hands close to your body, separated at shoulder width. Your arms should be fully extended.\n\n
2. The legs will be extended forward on top of the other bench. Your legs should be parallel to the floor while your torso is to be perpendicular to the floor. Have your partner place the dumbbell on your lap. Note: This exercise is best performed with a partner as placing the weight on your lap can be challenging and cause injury without assistance. This will be your starting position.\n\n
3. Slowly lower your body as you inhale by bending at the elbows until you lower yourself far enough to where there is an angle slightly smaller than 90 degrees between the upper arm and the forearm. Tip: Keep the elbows as close as possible throughout the movement. Forearms should always be pointing down.\n\n
4. Using your triceps to bring your torso up again, lift yourself back to the starting position while exhaling.\n\n
5. Repeat for the recommended amount of repetitions.
        </item>




 </string-array>
</resources>